Hi, and this lesson I will walk you through the chat interface in hit hubcopilot.
I will show you different features and controls with chat here and explain how it works.
So let's might restart with the chat options we have.
The first chat example we can use is the inline chat.
So you know how to browse inline chat you can that basically source somewhere in the code and click common plus i keyboard.
And you will see an inline chat. You can do same of course in terminal you also can click common i and you can use it.
So in line chat you can start directly from the digital terminal to get suggestions in place.
It's when you want to ask something short. The next chat example is the chat view.
You can click, you can open it, click and buy this icon. You will see the full cat window
place it inside. So you can ask longer queries, longer prompts, you can also use some chat controls here.
I will back to this controls a bit later. Also the next chat you can use it called a quick chat.
You can click on this drop down near the chat icon and click on a quick chat.
You can ask quickly some question when you call in Samsung and back into what you were doing. So
just for some quick responses which is not related to some place where your course or so.
Let's get back to our main chat interface. I will show you and explain you all the controls we
have here. So the first you can add a constant context. About context we have a separate lesson.
I will explain you in this lesson. The same about chat modes you can have ask,
agent already mode. I also will explain you all those modes in separate lessons because there
are a lot of information I can give you about it. So the next one is you can choose a chat model.
Results to the code offers various built-in language models. Some of faster for coding tasks
while others work better for planning and reasoning. So the least of models available here are
my variety based in yoga pilot subscription and of course my change over time. So you can also
add some models from other providers. If you click manage models you can choose a different provider
and provide some to top information some configuration. But we won't cover it on this lesson
because I guess for you will be enough to use some basic models. Okay next you can submit a chat
prompt. And with your course to your code you can make chat requests using your natural language
depending of course on the mode you can ask about your code you can get some suggestions at it.
I got across multiple files or use some specialized tools. Also chat responses can include
some rich content like generator for me, code, or division, function or calculator.
You will see it provides a text it provides you also mark down with the code block and different
controls. So about how to correctly ask the questions. So you can check my one of my first lessons
about popular use cases of your hard code pilot or developers. It was in the introduction section.
I provided there on a presentation a lot of prompt examples for different topics. So you can
just use them or get an idea of what you can use in general. You can also also can check prompt
examples from your hard code pilot. I provided the link in the resources for this lesson. They
also have some bass of the popular prompt examples. Okay the next feature you can use and it's
also a nice feature is the chat history. As you iterate to send multiple chat prompts in chat
session, Visual code uses the history of chat prompts and responses as the context for your current
chat prompt. For example, if I ask the next question, so it will have an context that I want to
implement some code for division, function for calculator. So I can just ask some follow up question
for example to ask editor or change the implementation or do something different way. So but like
if I want to start with a new context, I always can create a new chat, click here. And so
makes sense to create a new chat when you want to switch the content. You want to create a new
context. You just want to start asking about a separate topic. Also, you can view the old chat
history you have here. So you can switch between the chat. So there is some previous history
about the calculator. I don't know why it's not switching. Yep, let's switch to another one. So we
can also switch between histories. Another feature is that you can open your chat in a digital
tab or a separate windows. You can click on this three dots icon and click open chat in the
editor. It's a when you need to provide more bigger prompt. You want to create the code in a bigger
screen. For example, you also can open chat a new window. It might be useful if you use a second
monitor. You can move it to the second monitor or if you want to have a few chats about
with a different context at the same time. So you can also use the voice interactions. You see
this icon with microphone. The voice and control capabilities provided by the
videos to the code speech plugin. So when you click on this icon, it will suggest you to install
this extension. And then you can use the voice controls. You can use your voice dedicated chat
prompts. You can also use the command hate code. It's the voice command to start the voice session
with the power chat. Something like we have with hate series. So I hope this lesson about
chat interface was useful for you and now you know what every control means. And see you in the next
lesson.